Okay, hopefully you were able to give
that a shot. I'm going to show you a
solution now. So, there's my name. The
description is a mini calculator with
lots of functions.
All right, let's write a function called
add that takes two numbers and returns
the sum. I'm going to use modern syntax
here. So, I'm going to say const add add
equals and I'm going to accept two
numbers a and b. And I'm going to return
the results as a plus b because I um did
everything on one line. Um it's an
implied return thanks to this lambda.
And so that's the add function. And I'm
just going to copy that. And I'm going
to paste it. And I'm going to change the
name to multiply. And I'm going to do a
* b. I'm going to paste it. And change
this to divide. Oh, actually sorry.
Multiply is supposed to be here.
That was subtract. Forgot to do
subtract.
Subtract.
Change that to minus. Um
and then
got multiply.
Let's divide.
Um we'll change this to modulus.
And we'll change that operator to a
modulus operator.
Um
we'll change this one to power. Change
that to the exponentiation operator.
And then now we need to write a function
called calculate. So const calculate.
And it should take two numbers and a
function. And it should apply that
function to those two numbers. So, we'll
call our function with A and B and we'll
save that. And if you hold option shift
F, it should format everything on your
page or alt shift F if you're on
Windows. Now, we need to move all of
those functions into an external script
file. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to highlight all these
and I'm going to cut them. So, command X
or controlX if you're on Windows. Over
here, I'm going to create a new file and
I'm going to call this my functions.js.
And then I'm going to paste all of them
in. And then I'm going to hold option
shift F to format. And I'm going to
save. I know I'm going to need these
files in the other folder. So I'm going
to hold option and click. Or on Windows
you could hold alt and click and I'm
going to export all of these functions.
All right, they're all exported. Now I
can access add, subtract, multiply,
divide, modulus, and power and calculate
all in the other file. So, let's come
back over here. If I want to bring them
in, then I'm going to need to say that
my type is module, and I need to import
them. So, I'm going to say import,
add, subtract, multiply, divide,
modulus, and power. Let me double check
that that is all of them. Add, subtract,
multiply, divide, modulus, and power.
Oh, can't forget. Calculate and
calculate.
Calculate.
And I'm going to say from and then where
are these files? Well, I'm in function
project.html.
They are in my functions.js, meaning
they are in the same folder, which means
I can say dot slash for the same folder,
then say my functions.js.
All right, I successfully brought them
in. Now it wants me to call the function
once for each of the functions that I
previously defined. Well, all of them
take two numbers.
And I can actually take all of these
put them in a list. So what I'm going to
do is I'm going to say const my
functions
list and I'm going to put them all in
there. And then I'm going to run a loop.
I'm going to say for um
let that equal
um of my functions list. So what I'm
doing is I'm saying go through each
function here and store it here. Then
what I want to do is I want to alert
calling the calculate function with
three as the first number, four as the
second number and whatever function we
happen to be on. So what that will do is
it'll take add and then it will add
three and four. Then it'll take subtract
and it'll subtract four from three. Then
it'll multiply three and four. Divide
modulus and power and so on and so forth
as it goes through all of them. And I'm
actually going to move that under the
comment that applies to it.
And actually, it's alerting them as
well. So, I'm going to move that above.
And I'm going to save this. And let's go
over and see the results.
Oh, actually, it would help if we went
live. So, we'll hit go live. And we got
7 is 3 + 4. And that is correct. We get
- 1. 3 - 4 is - 1. 12.75.
three and 81. Um 3 to the 4th is
apparently 81. And so we have
successfully written all of these
functions in another file, added them to
a list so that we could loop through
them and call the calculate function by
passing in each one. And so I've put my
name and description. I'm going to add a
comment here. Bring in all the
functions. Um,
make them loopable.
And then I don't need that comment
anymore.
Um, this file looks good. Let's go look
over here. And each of those comments
very neatly describes the functions that
we've got. So, it looks like we are
done. And that concludes this solution.
Thanks for watching.